PHOEBE: Oh, hey, you guys, look.
Ugly Naked Guy's putting stuff in boxes.
ROSS:
Oh.
Huh. I'd say from the looks of it,
our naked buddy is moving.
Ironically, most of the boxes
seem to be labeled "Clothes."
Aw, I'm going to miss that big
old squishy butt.
And we're done
with the chicken fried rice.
Hey. Hey, if he's moving,
maybe I should try to get his place.
PHOEBE: Oh, yeah.
JOEY: Good idea.
It would be so cool
to live across from you guys.
Yeah, hey, then we could do
that telephone thing...
...you know, where you have a can,
we have a can...
...and it's connected by a string.
Or we could do
the actual telephone thing.
Oh, my God. I love this apartment.
Isn't it perfect?
I can't believe I never realized
how great it is.
That is because your eye
immediately goes to the big naked man.
PHOEBE:
It's amazing.
You better hurry up and fill out
an application, or I'll beat you to it.
Oh, heh.
Well, I never thought I'd say this, but I'm
gonna go use Ugly Naked Guy's bathroom.
Oh, look. There's Monica and Chandler.
Hey!
Hey, you guys! Hey!
Oh!
Aah! Aah!
Aah! Chandler and Monica.
Chandler and Monica.
Oh, my God.
- Chandler and Monica!
- Oh, my God!
Oh, my eyes! My eyes!
- Phoebe. Phoebe.
- Ow!
It's okay. It's okay.
- No, they're doing it!
- I know.
- I know. I know.
- You know?
Yes, I know, and Joey knows,
but Ross doesn't...
...so you have to stop screaming!
Hey, what's going on?
[YELLING]
- What?
RACHEL: Nothing.
Oh, God, we're just so excited
that you might get this apartment.
- Actually, it looks really good.
- Aah! It looks pretty good!
Get in here! Come on!
[ALL YELLING]
You mean whenever
Monica and Chandler were, like...
...doing laundry
or going grocery shopping?
All that time Monica spent on the phone
with sad Linda from camp?
Uh-huh.
Doing it, doing it, phone doing it.
I can't believe it.
I mean, I think it's great. For him.
She might be able to do better.
- Hey, you guys.
- Joey, come here. Come here.
Phoebe just found out
about Monica and Chandler.
You mean how they're friends
and nothing more?
No. No, Joey, she knows.
We were at Ugly Naked Guy's apartment
and saw them doing it through the window.
Actually, we saw them doing it
up against the window.
Okay, so now they know you know,
and they don't know Rachel knows?
Yes, but you know what?
It doesn't matter who knows what.
Now enough of us know
that we could just tell them we know.
Now all the lying and the secrets
will finally be over.
Or we could not tell them we know
and have a little fun of our own.
Well, what do you mean?
You know, every time they say
they're doing laundry...
...we'll give them laundry to do.
- Oh, I would enjoy that.
- No, no, no.
Wait, Rach, you know what would be
even more fun? Telling them.
- Yeah, no, I want to do Phoebe's thing.
- I can't take any...
You don't have to do anything.
Just don't tell them that we know.
No. I can't take any more secrets.
I got your secrets, I got their secrets.
I got secrets of my own, you know.
- You don't have any secrets.
- Oh, yeah?
Well, you don't know about Hugsy,
my bedtime penguin pal.
So, ahem, um...
How are we going to mess with them?
[JOEY GROANS]
Well, you could use your position
as the roommate.
And then I would use, you know,
the strongest tool at my disposal.
My sexuality.
- Hello, children.
ALL: Hey.
Okay. Watch, learn,
and don't eat my cookie.
- Hey.
Ooh. Wow, that jacket
looks great on you.
- Really?
- Yeah. The material looks so soft.
Oh, hello, Mr. Bicep.
You've been working out?
Well, I try to, you know, squeeze things.
[LAUGHING]
Are you okay?
Well, if you really wanna know...
Oh, I can't tell you this.
Phoebe, it's me,
you can tell me anything.
Well, actually, you're the one person
I can't tell this to.
And the one person I want to the most.
What's going on?
I think it's just, you know,
that I haven't been with a guy in so long...
...and you know how sometimes
you're looking for something...
...and you don't see that it's right there
in front of you, sipping coffee...
Oh, no. Have I said too much?
Well, just something to think about.
I know I will.
Ooh. Ha, ha.
- You are so cute.
- Heh.
How did you get to be so cute?
Well, my grandfather was Swedish.
And my grandmother was actually
a tiny little bunny.
Okay, now you're even cuter.
You know, that is a popular
opinion today, I must say.
What?
The weirdest thing happened
at the coffeehouse.
I think Phoebe was hitting on me.
What are you talking about?
I'm telling you,
I think Phoebe thinks I'm foxy.
- It's not possible.
- Ow.
I'm sorry, it's just Phoebe's just
always thought you were charming...
...in a sexless kind of way.
Oh, well, you know,
I can't hear that enough.
I'm sorry, I just think
you misunderstood her.
No, I didn't misunderstand, okay?
She was all over me.
She touched my bicep,
for crying out loud.
This bicep?
Well, it's not flexed right now.
Hey, Mon, what are you doing?
Want to come see a movie with us?
Uh, actually, I was going
to do some laundry.
- Chandler, you want to do it with me?
- Sure, I'll do it with you.
Okay, great. Hold on a second.
Unh. Here you go.
You don't mind, do you?
That would really help me out a lot. Thanks.
Ha, ha. You know what?
I don't think I have enough quarters.
PHOEBE:
Oh, I have quarters.
- Hey.
- Hey, Ross, any word on the apartment yet?
Well, I called over there, and it turns out
Ugly Naked Guy is subletting it himself.
And he's already had like 100 applicants.
ALL: Oh.
- No, no, I've got the edge.
I know it's not exactly ethical,
but I sent him a bribe...
...to tip the scales in my direction.
Yeah. Check it out,
you can see it from the window.
Oh, is it that pinball machine
with the big bow on it?
No.
That new mountain bike?
Well, what did you send?
A basket of mini muffins.
There's a whole table
of mini muffin baskets.
Which one did you send?
The small one.
What? You actually thought that basket
was gonna get you the apartment?
Well, yeah.
Someone sent us a basket at work once
and people went crazy over those muffins.
It was the best day.
Your work makes me sad.
Oh, man, I want that place so much.
And I was so sure
that was going to work.
There's 12 bucks
I'll never see again.
All right, we'd better go
if we're gonna catch that movie.
- Bye.
Bye, Chandler. I miss you already.
Okay, did you see that?
With the inappropriate, and the pinching?
Actually, I did.
So now do you believe
that she's attracted to me?
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
She knows about us.
Are you serious?
Phoebe knows,
and she's just trying to freak us out.
That's the only explanation for it.
Okay, but what about my pinchable butt
and my bulging biceps?
She knows.
Joey.
Yeah?
Phoebe knows about us.
Well, I didn't tell them.
Them? Who's "them"?
Uh, Phoebe and Joey.
Joey.
And Rachel.
Look, I would have told you,
but they made me promise not to tell.
- Oh, man.
- I'm sorry.
But, hey, it's over now, right?
Because you can tell them
you know they know...
...and I can go back to knowing
absolutely nothing.
- Unless...
- No, not "unless." This must end now.
Oh, man, they think they are so slick
messing with us.
But they don't know
that we know that they know.
- So...
- Ah, yes.
The messers become the messees.
[WHINES]
Oh, Ross, honey,
you gotta stop torturing yourself.
Why don't you just find
another apartment?
I've already looked at
like a thousand apartments this month.
None of them even compares
to that one.
You know what you should do?
You should find out what his hobbies are
and then use that to bond with him.
Yeah. Like if I wanted something
from Joey...
...I would strike up a conversation
about, say, um, sandwiches...
...or, uh, my underwear.
I'm listening.
See?
That is a great idea.
And I know Ugly Naked Guy because
we've been watching him for five years.
So that gives me back my edge. Ha, ha.
Let's see now. He had the trampoline.
- But he broke that.
- Well, he had gravity boots.
Yeah, he broke those too.
So he likes to break stuff.
Okay, I've got to go pick up Ben,
but I will figure something out.
Hey, didn't he used to have a cat?
I wouldn't bring that up.
It would probably just bum him out.
Poor cat never saw that big butt coming.
[PHONE RINGS]
Hello?
Oh, yeah, hey.
Hold on a second, she's right here.
[WHISPERS]
It's Chandler.
Oh.
Hello, you.
Hello, Phoebe,
I've been thinking about you all day.
Huh?
Well, you know that thing you said before?
I'd be lying if I said I wasn't intrigued.
Really?
Yeah. Listen, Joey won't be here tonight.
Why don't you come over
and I'll let you, uh, feel my bicep.
Or maybe more.
I'll have to get back to you on that.
Okay, bye.
Oh, my God. He wants me to come over
and feel his bicep and more.
- Are you kidding?
- No.
I cannot believe
he would do that to Mon...
Joey? Do they know that we know?
- No.
- Joey?
- They know you know.
- Ooh, I knew it.
Oh, I cannot believe those two.
They thought they could mess with us?
They're trying to mess with us?
They don't know that we know
they know we know.
And, Joey, you can't say anything.
Couldn't if I wanted to.
Good evening, sir.
My name is Ross Geller.
I'm one of the people
who applied for the apartment...
...and I realize that the competition
is fierce, but...
I'm sorry, I can't help but notice
that you're naked and...
I applaud you.
Man, I wish I was naked.
I mean, this looks so great.
That is how God intended it.
- Look at them. They're panicked.
- Oh, yeah, they're totally gonna back down.
Oh, yeah.
All right, if he wants a date,
he's going to get a date.
- I'm going to go in.
- Okay, okay.
Be sexy.
Please.
Little girl?
I'm a policeman.
Little girl.
Don't be afraid.
www.addic7ed.com
resync by Doomxknight
What's the difference
between men and women?
- Is this a joke?
- No, serious.
I never met a woman
who knew how to turn off a light.
They're born thinking in a switch,
it only goes one way.
On.
*** blond *** lit room.
I mean every woman, every lady has a ***,
I swear to God.
Come home,
house all lit up,
and my job, apparently because...
because my chromosomes happen
to be different
cause I then gotta walk through that house,
turn off every single
light this chick left on.
- Is that right?
- Yeah, baby.
Alright, Reverend Shane's preaching
to you now, boy.
The same chick, mind ya.
She'll bitch about global warming.
That's when Reverend Shane wants to
quote from the Guy Gospel and
say "Um, darling?"
"maybe you, and every other
pair of boobs on this planet
just figured out that the light switch
see, goes both ways,
"maybe we wouldn't have
so much global warming."
- You say that?
- Yeah.
Anyway, uh...
Polite version...
Still man, that... that earns me this.
This look and loathing
you would not believe.
And that's when
the exorcist voice pops out.
"You sound just like my damn father.
"Always, always yelling about the power bill,
"telling me to turn off the damn lights."
- What do you say to that?
- You know what I wanna say.
I wanna say, "Bitch, you mean to tell me
you've been hearing this your entire life
"and you are still too damn stupid
to learn how to turn off a switch?
You know...
I don't actually say that, tho.
- That would be bad.
- Yeah, go with the uh...
the polite version there...
- Very wise.
- Yes, sir.
So how's it with Lori, man?
She's good.
She's good at turning off lights.
Really good. I don't know
why sometimes ***
Not what I meant.
- We didn't have a great night.
- Look, man, I may have a...
fail to amuse with my sermon,
but I did try.
The least you could do is speak.
That's what she always says:
"Speak". "Speak".
You think I was the most closed mouth
son of a bitch you'd ever hear to hear her tell it.
Do you express your thoughts?
You share your feelings and that kind of stuff?
The thing is...
lately whenever I try...
everything I say makes her impatient,
like she didn't want to hear it after all.
It's like she's...
pissed at me all the time,
and I don't know why.
Look, man, that's just shit
couples go through.
Nah, it's... It's a phase.
- Last thing she said this morning?
- Mm?
Sometimes I wonder if you
even care about us at all.
She said that in front of our kid.
Imagine going to school
with that in your head.
Difference between men and women?
I would never say something
that cruel to her.
Certainly not in front of Carl.
All available units, high speed
pursuit in progress
Lincoln county units
request local assistance.
Highway 18 south GTAAD W217 243.
Proceed with extreme caution.
Suspects are two male Caucasians.
Be advised, they have fired
on police officers.
One Lindon county officer is wounded.
Unit 1, Unit 3, please ***.
18, 2 miles west of lnterstate 85
and we'll patch in Lindon County Sheriff radio.
Roger that. We're 5 minutes out
on the route 18 intersection.
Dispatch, Unit 1, Unit 3, we are 10-97
in code 100.
Highway 18, *** Interstate, please advise.
***
Sounds like they're chasing those idiots
up and down every back road we got.
Hey, we'll get them on one of
those video shows, you know,
like World's craziest police chases,
what do you think?
What I think, Leon, is that
you need to stay focused.
Make sure you got a round
in the chamber and your safety off.
Would be kind of cool to get on
one of them shows.
Holy shit.
- Gun, gun, gun.
- Put it down!
Put the gun down!
- Rick!
- I'm alright!
I saw you get tagged, man,
it scared the hell out of me.
Me too.
Son of a bitch shot me.
You believe that?
We'll get you a new vest.
Yeah.
Shane, you do not tell Lori
that happened. Ever.
You understand... Aah!
Rick! Rick!
No, no, no!
Shh, shh, shh.
No, no, no, no...
He's hurt!
***
You get that ambulance down here, you tell
them there's an officer down, you do it now!
Shh, shh, shh, hey, you look at me,
stay with me, you hear me? Shh, shh. okay.
Shh, shh, stay with me, you hear me?
Shh, shh, ok?
You stay with me, ok?
Hey, bud...
We're still here.
We're still hanging in.
Look, I'm sorry, man.
I'm mean watching the same crap
every time I come in here.
Everybody pitched in on these. They uh...
They wanted me to bring them down,
they send their love and they just...
They hope you come back real soon.
Linda and Diane from dispatch,
they picked these out.
You probably could tell, hmm?
I'll just set this on your side table, ok?
That vase has something special.
Fess up. Did you steal it from
your Grandma Gene's house.
I hope you left her that spoon collection.
Shane?
Shane, you in the john?
Nurse, help.
Nurse.
Help!
Lori!
Carl!
Lori! Carl!
Is this real?
Am I here?
Wake, wake up!
- Daddy, daddy!
- Carl...
Carl?
I found you...
Daddy, I got this sumbitch.
I'm gonna smack him dead.
He say something?
I thought I heard him say something.
- He called me Carl.
- Son, you know they don't talk.
Hey, mister!
What's that bandage for?
- What?
- What kind of wound?
You answer me, damn you!
What's your wound?
You tell me!
Or I will kill you.
Got that bandage changed out.
It was pretty rank.
What was? The wound?
- Gun shot.
- Gun shot?
What else? Anything?
Gun shot ain't enough?
Look, I ask and you answer,
It's common courtesy, right?
Did you get bit?
- Bit?
- Bit. Chewed.
Maybe scratch? Anything like that.
No, I got shot.
- Just shot?
- As far as I know.
Hey...
Just let me...
Feels cooler now.
Fever would have killed you by now.
- I don't think I have one.
- Be hard to miss.
Take a moment, eh?
Look how sharp it is.
You try anything...
I will kill you with it,
and don't you think I won't.
Come on up when you're able.
Come on.
This place...
It's Fred and Cindy Drake's.
Never met them.
I've been here. This is their place
It was empty when we got here.
Don't do that.
They'll see the light.
There's more of them out there than usual.
I never should have fired that gun today.
The sound draws them,
now they're all over the street.
Stupid... using a gun...
It all happened so fast...
- I didn't think.
- You shot that man today.
Man?
- No man... - What the hell was that
out of your mouth just now?
- It wasn't a man.
- You shot him.
In this street, out front, a man.
For him, you need glasses,
that was a walker.
Come on.
Sit down, before you fall down.
Here. Eat.
Daddy...
Blessing...
Yeah.
Father, we thank thee for this food...
Thy blessings...
We ask you to watch over us in these crazy days.
- Amen.
Hey, mister, do you even know
what is going on?
I woke up today.
In a hospital.
Came home, that's all I know.
- But you know about the dead people, right?
- Yeah, I saw a lot of that.
Out on the loading dock, hauling trucks.
No...
Not the one's they put down...
The one's they didn't. The walkers.
Like the one I shot today.
Cause he would have ripped into you.
Try to eat you, take him
some flesh at least.
But I guess if this is the first
you're hearing,
I know how it must sound...
- They're out there now, in the street?
- Yeah.
They're even more active
after dark sometimes.
Maybe it's the cool air or...
Hell, maybe it's just me
firing up that gun today.
But we'll be fine long as we stay quiet.
Probably wander off by morning.
Well, listen...
One thing I do know...
Don't you get bit!
We saw your bandage
and that's why we were afraid of.
Bites kill you.
The fever... burns you out.
But then after a while...
You come back.
Seen it happen...
Come on...
Carl...
He your son?
William..
He said his name today...
He's a little younger...
than your boy.
And he's with his mother?
I hope so.
- Dad?
- Yeah?
Did you ask him?
Your gun shot...
We got a little bet going.
My boy say you're a...
bank robber...
Yeah...
That's me. Deadly as Dillinger.
Kapow.
Sheriff's deputy.
Aha.
Hey, it's ok, daddy's here.
It's nothing.
One of them must've bumped a car...
- You sure?
- Happened once before.
Went off a few minutes.
Get the light, Dwayne.
It's the blue one, down the street.
Same one as last time.
I think we're ok.
That noise...
Will it bring more of them?
Nothing to do about it now.
Just have to wait 'em out till morning.
She's here.
Don't look.
Get away from the windows.
I said go! Come on!
Come on, quiet.
Shh, shh...
It's ok, here. Cry into the pillow.
Can you remember?
Shh...
She, uh...
She died in the other room, on that bed...
Nothin' I can do about it here...
That fever, man...
Her skin gave off heat like a furnace...
Should have put her down, I should
have put her down, I know that, but...
You know what...
I just didn't have it in me...
She's the mother of my child.
- You sure?
- They're dead.
They have to ask, at least one more time.
They're dead.
Except for something in the brain.
That's why it's gotta be the head.
You alright?
Need a moment?
They're alive.
My wife and son.
At least they were when they left.
How can you know?
- By the look of this place...
- I found empty drawers in the bedroom.
They packed some clothes. Not a lot.
But enough to travel.
You know anybody could've broken in here
and stolen clothes, right?
You see the framed photos on the walls?
Neither do I. Some random thief
took those too, you think?
My photo albums, family pictures, all gone.
Photo albums...
My wife...
Same thing...
Here I am, packing survival gear,
she's grabbing photo albums....
They're in Atlanta, I'll bet.
That's right.
- Why there?
- Refugee settle.
Huge, when they said it,
before the broadcast stopped.
Military protection, food, shelter...
They told people to go there.
Said to be safest.
Plus they got that disease place.
Center for Disease Control.
Said they were working on
how to solve this thing.
Gas and light have been down
for maybe a month.
Station got its own propane system.
Pilot's still on.
Oh, my Lord.
Hot water!
- Whoo!
- That feels good, right?
Dwayne...
Dress in room back there.
What you say, Dwayne?
Thank you.
Mhm.
Atlanta sounds like a good deal.
Safer anyway. People...
That's where we were heading.
Things got crazy. Man, you won't believe.
The panic...
Streets won't fit to be on,
and then we'll...
My wife...
couldn't travel. no, not with our herd,
so we had to find a place to lay low.
And then, after she died...
We just stayed hunkered down.
I guess we just froze in place.
Plan to move on?
Haven't worked up to it yet. (*)
A lot of it's gone missing.
Dad, can I learn to shoot?
I'm old enough.
Hell yes you're going to learn.
We gotta do it carefully, teach you
to respect the weapon.
That's right. It's not a toy.
You pull the trigger, you have to mean it.
Always remember that, Dwayne.
Yes, sir.
Here.
Go on.
Take that one.
Nothing fancy.
Scope's accurate.
Conserve your ammo. Goes faster than
you think. Especially at target practice.
Dwayne.
- Yeah?
- Take this to the car.
You sure you won't come along?
A few more days...
By the end, Dwayne will know how
to shoot and I won't be so rusty.
You got one better.
I'll turn mine on, a few minutes
every day at dawn.
You get up there, that's how you find me.
- You think they're here?
- Can't afford not to.
- Not anymore.
- Look, just one thing.
They may not seem
like much one at a time...
but in a group all round up and hungry...
- They you watch your ass.
- You too.
You a good man, Rick.
I hope you find your wife and son.
Be seeing you, Dwayne.
- Take care of your old man.
- Yes, sir.
Leon Bessi?
Didn't think much of him.
Careless and dumb, but...
can't leave him like this.
You know, if they hear the shot..?
- Let's not be here when they show up.
- Let's go, son.
Come on.
Read your comic books a while.
Daddy'll be upstairs.
- Daddy?
- It's alright, Dwayne.
You stay there, son.
Don't come up here.
Come on, baby.
I'm sorry this happened to you.
Come on, come on.
Broadcasting on emergency channel.
We'll be approaching Atlanta on Highway 85.
Anybody reads, please respond.
Hello. Hello.
Can anybody hear my voice?
Anybody out there?
Anybody hears me, please respond.
Hello, can you hear my voice?
Hello? Hello? Can anybody hear my voice?
Hey? Hello?
- Can you hear my voice?
- Yes, I can hear you.
You're coming through. Over.
Anybody who reads, please respond.
Broadcasting on emergency channel.
We'll be approaching Atlanta
on Highway 85.
Anybody reads, please respond.
We're just outside the city.
Damnit.
Hello?
He couldn't hear me. I couldn't warn him.
Try to raise him again.
Come on, son. You know best
how to work this thing,
Hello, hello, is the person
who calls still on the air?
This is officer Shane Walsh, broadcasting
a person unknown, please respond.
He's gone.
There are others. It's not just us.
Yeah, We knew there would be, right,
that's why we let the CB on.
Lot of good it's been doing.
And I've been saying for a week,
we ought to put signs up on 85
to warn people away from the city.
Folks got no idea
what they're getting into.
We don't have enough time.
I think we need to make time.
Yeah, that, uh...
That's a luxury we can't afford.
We are surviving here.
We are day to day.
And who the hell would you propose to send?
I'll go. Give me a vehicle.
Nobody goes anywhere alone, you know that.
Yes, sir.
Hey, hey, hey, come on, take a sit, buddy.
You're alright, go on, you're alright.
What, you're pissed at me?
Well pissing me all you want
won't gonna change anything.
I'm not putting you in danger, okay?
I'm not doing it for anything.
I make you feel like sometimes you wanna
slap me outside the head...
I'll tell you what, girl. You feel that need,
you go right ahead. I'm right here.
You cannot walk off like that,
all half-cocked.
Look, if you don't wanna do it for
my sake or for your sake, that's fine.
But just...
You do it for him.
That boy has been through too much.
And he's not losing his mother too, ok?
Okay.
Ok, fine.
You tell me okay.
It's not hard.
Hey...
Mom?
What's up, buddy? She's in there, go on.
Hey.
I don't want you to worry.
Your mom is not going anywhere.
Okay?
- Yeah? Yeah? Yeah? Go finish your chores.
- Okay.
Hello?
Police officer out here.
Can I borrow some gas?
Hello?
Anybody home?
Easy now, easy.
I'm not gonna hurt you.
Nothing like that.
More like a proposal.
Atlanta's just down the road ways.
It's safe there.
Food, shelter, people,
other horses too, I bet.
How's that sound?
There we go. Good boy.
Good boy. Now come with me.
Come with me.
Let's go easy, ok?
I haven't done this for years.
Easy. Easy, boy. Easy, easy, easy.
Let's go.
Steady. It's just a few.
Nothing we can't outrun.
Okay, whoa whoa whoa.
Lori, Carl, I'm sorry.
Hey, you.
Dumb ass.
Hey, you in the tank.
Cozy in there?
13 meters. You should see it.
Okay, take her up and over the bow rail.
Okay, Mir-2, we're going over the bow.
Stay with us.
Okay, quiet. We're rolling.
Seeing her coming out of the darkness
like a ghost ship ...
still gets me every time.
To see the sad ruin of the great ship,
sitting here ...
where she landed at 2:30 in the morning
of April 15, 1912 ...
after her long fall ...
from the world above.
You're so full of shit, boss.
Dive 6.
Here we are again on the deck of Titanic.
2½ miles down.
3,821 meters.
The pressure outside
is 3½ tons per square inch.
These windows are 9 inches thick
and if they go ...
it's sayonara in 2 microseconds.
All right, enough of that bullshit.
Just put her down on the roof
of the officers' quarters like yesterday.
Sure.
Okay, Mir-2, we're landing
right over the Grand Staircase.
You guys set to launch?
Yeah, Brock, launching Dunkin now.
Go, Charlie.
- All right, tether out.
- Tether out.
Okay, Brock,
we're dropping down along the hull.
Yeah, roger that. Okay, drop down,
and go into the first-class gangway door.
I want you guys working the "D" deck
reception area and the dining saloon.
Copy that.
- Tether out.
Okay, now left. Now left. Left, left.
Snoop Dog is on the move.
We're headed down the stairwell.
Okay, Lewis, drop down to "B" deck.
"A" deck.
- Give me some rope, Captain.
- "B" deck. Get in there.
- Watch the door frame. Watch it.
- I see it. I got it.
We're good. Just chill, boss.
Okay, make your turn.
- Cable out, Captain.
- Make your turn. Watch the wall.
Brock, we're at the piano. You copy?
Copy that.
Right there.
- That's it. That's the bedroom door.
- I see it.
We're in. We're in, baby. We're there.
That's Hockley's bed.
That's where the son of a bitch slept.
Oops. Somebody left the water running.
Hold it. Just a second.
Go back to the right.
That wardrobe door. Get closer.
- You're smelling something, boss.
- I want to see what's under it.
Give me my hands, man.
All right.
- Take it easy. It might come apart.
- Okay.
Okay, go. Flip it over. Go. Turn over.
Keep going. Go.
Okay, drop it.
Oh, baby. Are you seeing this, boss?
It's payday, boys.
Cha-ching!
- We did it, Bobby.
- We brought it back.
Oh, yeah! You the man!
Who's the best, baby? Say it.
You are, Lewis.
- Bobby, my cigar.
- Right here.
Okay, crack her open.
Let me get around. Hang on.
- You getting it?
- Got it.
Shit.
No diamond.
You know, boss,
this same thing happened to Geraldo ...
and his career never recovered.
Turn the camera off.
Brock. The partners would like to know
how it's going.
Hey, Dave. Barry, hi.
Look, it wasn't in the safe.
Don't worry about it. There are
still plenty of places it could be.
Hell, yes.
The floor debris in the suite,
the mother's room ...
- The purser's safe on "C" deck.
- Jimmy Hoffa's briefcase.
A dozen other places.
Guys, look, you just got to trust
my instincts. I know we're close.
We just got to go through
a little process of elimination.
Hang on a second.
- Let me see that.
- We might have something here, guys.
- Where's the photograph of the necklace?
- We'll call you right back.
I'll be goddamned.
Treasure hunter Brock Lovett
is best known for finding Spanish gold.
It's okay, I'll feed you in a minute.
He has chartered Russian subs to reach
the most famous shipwreck of all ...
the Titanic.
He's with us live via satellite,
from the research ship Keldysh ...
in the North Atlantic.
- Hello, Brock.
- Hello, Tracy.
Of course, everyone knows
the familiar stories of Titanic.
You know, the nobility of the band
playing to the very end and all that.
But what I'm interested in
are the untold stories ...
the secrets locked deep inside
the hull of Titanic.
And we're out here using robot technology
to go further into the wreck ...
than anybody has ever done before.
Your expedition is at the center
of a storm ...
of controversy over salvage rights,
and even ethics.
Many are calling you a grave-robber.
Nobody ever called the recovery
of the artifacts from King Tut's tomb ...
- What is it?
- Turn that up, dear.
I have museum-trained experts
sent out here making sure ...
that these relics are preserved
and catalogued properly.
Take a look at this drawing
that we found just today.
A piece of paper that's been underwater
for 84 years ...
and my team are able to preserve it intact.
Should this have remained unseen
at the bottom of the ocean for eternity?
We can see it and ...
I'll be goddamned.
Brock, there's a satellite call for you.
Bobby, we're launching. See these
submersibles going in the water?
Trust me, buddy,
you want to take this call.
This better be good.
- You got to speak up. She's kind of old.
- Great.
This is Brock Lovett.
How can I help you, Mrs. ...
Calvert. Rose Calvert.
Mrs. Calvert?
I was just wondering if you had found
the "Heart of the Ocean" yet, Mr. Lovett.
Told you you wanted to take the call.
All right, you have my attention, Rose.
Can you tell us who the woman
in the picture is?
Oh, yes. The woman in the picture is me.
She's a goddamn liar!
Some nutcase seeking money or publicity.
God only knows why!
Like that Russian babe, Anesthesia.
They're inbound!
Rose Dewitt Bukater died on the Titanic
when she was 17, right?
That's right.
If she had lived, she'd be over 100 by now.
101 next month.
Okay, so she's a very old goddamn liar.
Look, I've already done the background
on this woman ...
all the way back to the '20s,
when she was working as an actress.
An actress.
There's your first clue, Sherlock.
Her name was Rose Dawson back then.
Then she marries this guy named Calvert.
They move to Cedar Rapids
and she punches out a couple of kids.
Now Calvert's dead, and from what I hear,
Cedar Rapids is dead.
And everybody
who knows about the diamond ...
is supposed to be dead or on this boat,
but she knows.
Doesn't exactly travel light, does she?
Hurry up, give him a hand!
Mrs. Calvert, I'm Brock Lovett.
Welcome to the Keldysh.
Okay, let's get her inside there.
- Hi, Miss Calvert.
- Hi.
- Welcome to the Keldysh.
- Thanks.
Yes?
- Are your staterooms all right?
- Oh, yes, very nice.
Have you met my granddaughter, Lizzy?
She takes care of me.
We met just a few minutes ago.
Remember, Nana, up on deck?
Oh, yeah ...
There. That's nice.
Have to have my pictures when I travel.
Can I get you anything?
Is there anything you'd like?
Yes.
I would like to see my drawing.
Louis XVI wore a fabulous stone
called the Blue Diamond of the Crown.
It disappeared in 1792.
About the same time old Louis
lost everything from the neck up.
The theory goes that the
crown diamond was chopped, too.
Re-cut into a heart-like shape that
became known as the "Heart of the Ocean".
Today, it would be worth
more than the Hope Diamond.
It was a dreadful, heavy thing.
I only wore it this once.
You actually think this is you, Nana?
It is me, dear.
Wasn't I a dish?
I tracked it down
through insurance records.
An old claim that was settled
under terms of absolute secrecy.
Can you tell me
who the claimant was, Rose?
I should imagine someone named Hockley.
Nathan Hockley. That's right.
Pittsburgh steel tycoon.
The claim was for a diamond necklace
his son, Caledon, bought his fiancée, you.
A week before he sailed on Titanic.
It was filed right after the sinking.
So the diamond had to have gone down
with the ship.
You see the date?
April 14, 1912.
Which means if your grandmother
is who she says she is ...
she was wearing the diamond
the day the Titanic sank.
And that makes you my new best friend.
These are some of the things
we recovered from your stateroom.
This was mine.
How extraordinary!
And it looks the same as it did
the last time I saw it.
The reflection has changed a bit.
Are you ready to go back to Titanic?
Here we go.
She hits the 'berg on the starboard side.
She kind of bumps along, punching holes
like Morse code along the side ...
below the water line.
Then the forward compartments
start to flood.
Now, as the water level rises,
it spills over the watertight bulkheads ...
which, unfortunately,
don't go any higher than "E" deck.
So now, as the bow goes down,
the stern rises up, slow at first ...
then faster and faster, until finally,
she's got her whole ass sticking in the air.
And that's a big ass.
We're talking 20,000, 30,000 tons.
Okay? And the hull's not designed to deal
with that pressure.
So what happens?
She splits, right down to the keel ...
and the stern falls back level.
Then as the bow sinks, it pulls the stern
vertical and then finally detaches.
Now the stern section kind of bobs there
like a cork for a couple of minutes ...
floods, and finally goes under
about 2:20 am ...
2 hours and 40 minutes
after the collision.
The bow section planes away,
landing about a ½ a mile away ...
going 20, 30 knots
when it hits the ocean floor.
Pretty cool, huh?
Thank you for that fine
forensic analysis, Mr. Bodine.
Of course,
the experience of it was —
somewhat different.
Will you share it with us?
- I'm taking her to rest.
- No.
- Come on, Nana.
- No!
Give me the tape recorder.
Tell us, Rose.
It's been 84 years.
It's okay. Just try to remember
anything, anything at all.
Do you want to hear this
or not, Mr. Lovett?
It's been 84 years ...
and I can still smell the fresh paint.
The china had never been used.
The sheets had never been slept in.
Titanic was called "The Ship of Dreams".
And it was.
It really was.
All third-class passengers
with a forward berth ...
this way, please!
This queue! Right here ...
- It's a big boat, huh?
- Daddy, it's a ship.
You're right.
I don't see what all the fuss is about.
It doesn't look any bigger
than the Mauretania.
You can be blasé about some things,
Rose, but not about Titanic.
It's over 100 feet longer than
Mauretania, and far more luxurious.
Your daughter is far too difficult
to impress, Ruth.
So this is the ship
they say is unsinkable.
It is unsinkable.
God himself could not sink this ship.
Sir, you have to check your baggage
through the main terminal.
It's round that way, sir.
I put my faith in you, good sir.
Now, kindly see my man.
Yes, sir. It's my pleasure, sir.
If I can do anything at all ...
Yes, right.
All the trunks from that car there.
12 from here.
And the safe, to the parlor suite,
rooms B-52, 54, 56.
Ladies, we better hurry. Come along.
- My coat?
- I have it, miss.
Queue here for health inspection.
All third-class passengers
queue here for health inspection.
Chin up.
- Welcome aboard, ma'am.
- Welcome to Titanic.
It was the ship of dreams
to everyone else.
To me, it was a slave ship ...
taking me back to America in chains.
Outwardly, I was everything
a well brought up girl should be.
Inside, I was screaming.
Jack, you are pazzo.
You bet everything we have.
When you got nothing,
you got nothing to lose.
Sven?
Bet.
All right.
Moment of truth.
Somebody's life is about to change.
Brizio?
- Niente.
Olaf?
Nothing.
Sven?
2 pair.
I'm sorry, Fabrizio.
Che sorry, ma vaffanculo!
Did you bet all our money?
I'm sorry, you're not going to
see your mom again for a long time.
'Cause we're going to America.
Full house, boys.
Come on.
I'm going home!
- I'm going home.
- I go to America!
No, mate.
Titanic go to America, in 5 minutes.
Shit, Fabri. Come on. Come on, here.
We're riding in high style now.
We're a couple of regular swells.
We're practically goddamn royalty,
ragazzo mio.
You see? Is my destino.
Like I told you,
I go to America to be millionaire.
- You are pazzo.
- Maybe, but I've got the tickets.
- I thought you were fast.
- Aspetta!
Wait! Hey, wait!
We're passengers! Passengers!
Have you been through
the inspection queue?
Of course.
Anyway, we don't have any lice.
We're Americans, both of us.
Right. Come aboard.
We're the luckiest sons of bitches
in the world. You know that?
Goodbye!
- You know somebody?
- Of course not. That's not the point.
- Goodbye. I'll miss you.
- Goodbye!
- Goodbye.
- I will never forget you!
Come with me, darling. Let's go.
G-60.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Right here.
How you doing? Jack.
Nice to meet you.
Jack Dawson. Nice to meet you.
How you doing?
Who says you get top bunk?
This is your private
promenade deck, sir.
Would you be requiring anything?
Excuse me.
- This one?
- No.
It had a lot of faces on it.
This is the one.
Would you like all of them out, miss?
Yes, we need a little color in this room.
Put it in there. In the wardrobe.
God, not those finger-paintings again.
They certainly were a waste of money.
The difference between Cal's taste
in art and mine is that I have some.
They're fascinating ...
like being inside a dream or something.
There's truth, but no logic.
- What's the artist's name?
- Something Picasso.
Something Picasso. He won't amount
to a thing. He won't, trust me.
- Put the Degas in the bedroom.
- At least they were cheap.
Put it in the wardrobe.
At Cherbourg, a woman came aboard
named Margaret Brown.
We all called her Molly.
History would call her
the "Unsinkable Molly Brown".
I wasn't about to wait
all day for you, sonny.
Here, if you think you can manage.
Her husband had struck gold,
someplace out west.
And she was what mother called
"New Money. "
By the next afternoon,
we were steaming west ...
from the coast of Ireland ...
with nothing out ahead of us but ocean.
Take her to sea, Mr. Murdoch.
Let's stretch her legs.
Yes, sir.
- All ahead full, Mr. Moody.
- Very good, sir.
All ahead full.
All ahead full!
Come on, lads, step lively.
What's the reading?
All right! Let's stoke her right up!
We go full ahead!
Come on, right back to work.
21 knots, sir.
Hey, look!
See it?
There's another one. See him?
Look at that one! Look at him jump!
I can see the Statue of Liberty already.
Very small, of course.
I'm the king of the world!
She's the largest moving object ever made
by the hand of man in all history.
And our master shipbuilder, Mr. Andrews,
here, designed her from the keel plates up.
I may have knocked her together,
but the idea was Mr. Ismay's.
He envisioned a steamer
so grand in scale ...
and so luxurious in its appointments that
its supremacy would never be challenged.
And here she is,
willed into solid reality.
Hear, hear.
The salmon.
You know I don't like that, Rose.
She knows.
We'll both have the lamb.
Rare, with very little mint sauce.
You like lamb, right, sweet pea?
Sausage.
You gonna cut her meat for her,
too, there, Cal?
Hey, who thought of the name Titanic?
- Was it you, Bruce?
- Yes, actually.
I wanted to convey sheer size.
And size means stability, luxury ...
and above all, strength.
Do you know of Dr. Freud, Mr. Ismay?
His ideas about
the male preoccupation with size ...
might be of particular interest to you.
What's gotten into you?
Excuse me.
I do apologize.
She's a pistol, Cal.
Hope you can handle her.
I may have to start minding
what she reads from now on ...
won't I, Mrs. Brown?
Freud, who is he? Is he a passenger?
The ship is nice?
Yeah, it's an Irish ship.
Is English, no?
No, it was built in Ireland.
15,000 Irishmen built this ship.
Solid as a rock. Big Irish hands.
Well, that's typical.
First-class dogs come down here
to take a shit.
Lets us know where we rank
in the scheme of things.
Like we could forget.
I'm Tommy Ryan.
- Jack Dawson.
- Hello.
- Fabrizio.
- Hi.
Do you make any money
with your drawings?
Forget it, boyo.
You'd as like have angels
fly out of your arse ...
as get next to the likes of her.
I saw my whole life
as if I'd already lived it.
An endless parade of parties
and cotillions ...
yachts and polo matches.
Always the same narrow people,
the same mindless chatter.
I felt like I was standing at
a great precipice ...
with no one to pull me back.
No one who cared ...
or even noticed.
Don't do it.
Stay back.
Don't come any closer.
Come on. Just give me your hand,
I'll pull you back over.
No! Stay where you are.
I mean it.
I'll let go.
No, you won't.
What do you mean, no I won't?
Don't presume to tell me what I will
and will not do. You don't know me.
Well, you would have done it already.
You're distracting me. Go away.
I can't. I'm involved now.
You let go, and I'm gonna have
to jump in there after you.
Don't be absurd.
- You'll be killed.
- I'm a good swimmer.
The fall alone will kill you.
It would hurt.
I'm not saying it wouldn't.
To tell you the truth,
I'm a lot more concerned ...
about that water being so cold.
How cold?
Freezing.
Maybe a couple of degrees over.
You ever ...
You ever been to Wisconsin?
What?
They have some of the coldest
winters around.
I grew up there, near Chippewa Falls.
I remember, when I was a kid,
me and my father ...
we went ice fishing
out on Lake Wissota.
- Ice fishing is, you know, where you —
- I know what ice fishing is.
Sorry.
You just seem like,
you know, kind of an indoor girl.
Anyway, I ...
I fell through some thin ice.
And I'm telling you ...
water that cold ...
like right down there ...
it hits you like a 1,000 knives
stabbing you all over your body.
You can't breathe. You can't think.
Least, not about anything but the pain.
Which is why I'm not looking forward
to jumping in there after you.
Like I said ...
I don't have a choice.
I guess I'm kind of hoping you'll
come back over the rail an ...
and get me off the hook here.
You're crazy.
That's what everybody says bu ...
but with all due respect, miss ...
I'm not the one hanging off
the back of a ship here.
Come on.
Give me your hand.
You don't want to do this.
I'm Jack Dawson.
Rose Dewitt Bukater.
I'll have to get you
to write that one down.
Come on.
I got you. Come on.
Come on!
Help, please!
- Please, help me!
- Listen to me. I've got you.
I won't let go.
Now pull yourself up. Come on!
Come on. That's right.
You can do it.
I got you.
What's all this?
You stand back!
And don't move an inch!
Fetch the master-at-arms.
This is completely unacceptable.
What made you think you could
put your hands on my fiancée?
Look at me, you filth!
- Cal.
- What do you think you were doing?
Cal, stop. It was an accident.
An accident?
It was.
Stupid, really.
I was leaning over and I slipped.
I was leaning far over to see the ...
- Propellers?
- Propellers, and I slipped.
And I would have gone overboard,
but Mr. Dawson here saved me.
And almost went over himself.
She wanted to see the propellers.
Like I said,
women and machinery do not mix.
Was that the way of it?
Yeah, that was pretty much it.
Well, the boy's a hero, then.
Good for you, son. Well done.
So, it's all's well and
back to our brandy, eh?
- Aha.
Look at you. You must be freezing.
Let's get you inside.
Err ... perhaps a little
something for the boy?
Of course.
Mr. Lovejoy ...
I think a 20 should do it.
Is that the going rate
for saving the woman you love?
Rose is displeased.
What to do?
I know.
Perhaps you could join us
for dinner tomorrow evening.
To regale our group
with your heroic tale.
Sure. Count me in.
Good. It's settled then.
This should be interesting.
Can I bum a smoke?
You'll want to tie those.
It's interesting.
The young lady slipped so suddenly ...
and you still had time to remove
your jacket and your shoes.
I know you've been melancholy.
I don't pretend to know why.
I intended to save this ...
until the engagement gala next week.
But I thought, tonight.
Good gracious!
Perhaps as a reminder
of my feelings for you.
- Is it a —
- Diamond? Yes.
56 carats to be exact.
It was worn by Louis XVI.
And they called it "Le Coeur de la Mer".
- The "Heart of the Ocean".
- The "Heart of the Ocean". Yes.
It's overwhelming.
It's for royalty.
We are royalty, Rose.
You know, there is nothing
I couldn't give you.
There is nothing I'd deny you ...
if you would not deny me.
Open your heart to me, Rose.
I've been on my own since I was 15.
Since my folks died.
And I had no brothers or sisters
or close kin in that part of the country.
So I lit on out of there
and I haven't been back since.
You can just call me
a tumbleweed blowing in the wind.
Well, Rose, we've walked
about a mile around this boat deck ...
chewed over how great
the weather's been and how I grew up ...
but I reckon that's not
why you came to talk to me, is it?
- Mr. Dawson, I —
- Jack.
Jack ...
I want to thank you for what you did.
Not just for pulling me back ...
- but for your discretion.
- You're welcome.
Look ...
I know what you must be thinking:
"Poor little rich girl.
What does she know about misery?"
No.
That's not what I was thinking.
What I was thinking was ...
what could have happened to this girl
to make her think she had no way out?
Well, I ...
It was everything.
It was my whole world
and all the people in it.
And the inertia of my life ...
plunging ahead,
and me, powerless to stop it.
God, look at that thing.
You'd have gone straight
to the bottom.
500 invitations have gone out.
All of Philadelphia society
will be there.
And all the while, I feel I'm  ...
standing in the middle of
a crowded room ...
screaming at the top of my lungs,
and no one even looks up.
Do you love him?
Pardon me?
You're being very rude.
You shouldn't be asking me this.
It's a simple question.
Do you love the guy or not?
This is not a suitable conversation.
Why can't you
just answer the question?
This is absurd.
You don't know me
and I don't know you ...
and we are not having
this conversation at all.
You are rude and uncouth
and presumptuous and ...
I am leaving now.
Jack, Mr. Dawson,
it's been a pleasure.
I sought you out to thank you
and now I have thanked you —
And you've insulted me.
Well, you deserved it.
- Right.
- I thought you were leaving.
- I am.
You are so annoying.
Wait, I don't have to leave.
This is my part of the ship.
You leave.
Well, well, well!
Now who's being rude?
What is this stupid thing
you're carrying around?
So, what are you,
an artist or something?
These are rather good.
They're — they're very good, actually.
Jack, this is exquisite work.
They didn't think too much
of them in old Paree.
Paris?
You do get around for a ...
Well, a person of limited means.
Go on, a poor guy. You can say it.
Well, well, well.
And these were drawn from life?
That's one of the good things
about Paris.
Lots of girls willing to take
their clothes off.
You liked this woman.
You used her several times.
Well, she had beautiful hands,
you see?
I think you must have had
a love affair with her.
No, no, no, no — just with her hands.
She was a one-legged prostitute.
See?
She had a good sense of humor, though.
And this lady ...
she used to sit
at this bar every night ...
wearing every piece of jewelry
she owned just ...
waiting for her long lost love.
We called her Madame Bijoux.
See, her clothes are all moth-eaten.
Well, you have a gift, Jack.
You do.
- You see people.
- I see you.
And?
You wouldn't have jumped.
But the purpose of university
is to find a suitable husband.
Rose has already done that.
Look, here comes that vulgar
"Brown" woman.
Quickly, get up
before she sits with us.
Hello, girls.
I was hoping I'd catch you at tea.
We're awfully sorry. You missed it.
The Countess and I were just off
to take the air on the boat deck.
What a lovely idea.
I need to catch up on my gossip.
Countess.
You've not yet lit
the last 4 boilers?
No, I don't see the need.
We are making excellent time.
The press knows the size of Titanic.
Now, I want them to marvel at her speed.
We must give them
something new to print.
This maiden voyage of Titanic
must make headlines.
Mr. Ismay ...
I would prefer not to push the engines
until they've been properly run in.
Of course, I'm just a passenger.
I leave it to your good offices
to decide what's best.
But what a glorious end
to your final crossing ...
if we were to get into New York
on Tuesday night and surprise them all.
Make the morning papers.
Retire with a bang, eh, E.J.?
Good man.
Well, after that, I worked
on a squid boat in Monterey,
then I went down to Los Angeles
to the pier in Santa Monica ...
and started doing portraits there
for 10 cents a piece.
Why can't I be like you, Jack?
Just head out for the horizon
whenever I feel like it.
Say we'll go there sometime,
to that pier ...
even if we only ever
just talk about it.
No, we'll do it.
We'll drink cheap beer,
we'll ride on the roller coaster
till we throw up.
Then we'll ride horses on the beach,
right in the surf.
But you'll have to do it like a real
cowboy, none of that side-saddle stuff.
- You mean, one leg on each side?
- Yeah.
- Can you show me?
- Sure, if you like.
Teach me to ride like a man.
And chew tobacco like a man.
And spit like a man.
What, they didn't teach you that
in finishing school?
No.
Come on, I'll show you. Let's do it.
I'll show you how, come on.
- Jack, no.
- Come on.
- No. Wait, Jack.
No, Jack. I couldn't possibly, Jack.
Watch closely.
That's disgusting.
All right, your turn.
That was pitiful.
Come on, you really gotta hawk it back.
Get some leverage to it,
use your arms ...
arc your neck.
You see the range on that thing?
Okay, go.
- That was better. You got to work on it.
- Really?
Really try to hawk it up
and get some body to it. You gotta ...
Mother.
May I introduce Jack Dawson?
Charmed, I'm sure.
The others were gracious
and curious ...
about the man who'd saved my life.
But my mother looked at him
like an insect.
A dangerous insect
which must be squashed quickly.
Jack, sounds like you're a good man
to have around in a sticky spot.
Why do they always insist on
announcing dinner ...
like a damn cavalry charge?
Shall we go dress, Mother?
See you at dinner, Jack.
Son?
Son!
Do you have the slightest comprehension
of what you're doing?
Not really.
You're about to go into the snake pit.
What are you planning to wear?
I figured. Come on.
I was right.
You and my son
are just about the same size.
Pretty close.
You shine up like a new penny.
Good evening, sir.
There are several thousand tons
of Hockley steel in this very ship.
- Which part?
- All the right ones, of course.
Then we'll know who to hold accountable
if there's a problem.
- Where's my daughter?
- She'll be along.
There is the Countess.
- Hello, my dear.
- Good evening, Cal.
So good to see you.
I saw that in a nickelodeon once
and I always wanted to do it.
I'll see you at dinner.
Darling ...
surely you remember Mr. Dawson.
Dawson.
That's amazing.
You could almost pass
for a gentleman.
Almost.
Extraordinary.
My dear, it's delightful to see you.
What a remarkable voyage this is.
- It's mad, isn't it?
- Completely lunatic.
There's the Countess of Rothes.
And that's John Jacob Astor ...
the richest man on the ship.
His little wifey there, Madeleine,
is my age, and in a delicate condition.
See how she's trying to hide it?
Quite the scandal.
And that's Benjamin Guggenheim
and his mistress, Madame Aubert.
Mrs. Guggenheim is at home
with the children, of course.
And over here, we have Sir Cosmo
and Lucile, Lady Duff-Gordon.
She designs naughty lingerie,
among her many talents.
Very popular with the royals.
Congratulations, Hockley.
She's splendid.
Why, thank you.
- Care to escort a lady to dinner?
- Certainly.
Sweet pea?
Ain't nothing to it, is there, Jack?
Remember, they love money.
So just pretend like you own a
gold mine and you're in the club.
Hey, Astor.
Hello, Molly, nice to see you.
J.J., Madeleine,
I'd like you to meet Jack Dawson.
- How do you do?
- Pleasure.
Well, Jack ...
are you of the Boston Dawsons?
No, the Chippewa Falls
Dawsons, actually.
Oh, yes.
He must have been nervous,
but he never faltered.
They assumed he was one of them.
Heir to a railroad fortune, perhaps.
New money, obviously,
but still a member of the club.
Mother, of course,
could always be counted upon.
Tell us of the accommodations
in steerage, Mr. Dawson.
I hear they're quite good
on this ship.
The best I've seen, ma'am.
Hardly any rats.
Mr. Dawson is joining us
from the third class.
He was of some assistance
to my fiancée last night.
It turns out that Mr. Dawson
is quite a fine artist.
He was kind enough to show me
some of his work today.
Rose and I differ somewhat
in our definition of fine art.
Not to impugn your work, sir.
Are these all for me?
Just start from the outside
and work your way in.
He knows every rivet in her,
don't you, Thomas?
Your ship is a wonder,
Mr. Andrews. Truly.
Thank you, Rose.
How do you take your caviar, sir?
No caviar for me, thanks.
Never did like it much.
And where exactly do you live,
Mr. Dawson?
Right now, my address
is the RMS Titanic.
After that, I'm on God's good humor.
And how is it you have means to travel?
I work my way from place to place.
You know, tramp steamers and such.
But I won my ticket on Titanic here
at a lucky hand at poker.
A very lucky hand.
All life is a game of luck.
A real man makes his own luck,
Archie. Right, Dawson?
And you find that sort of rootless
existence appealing, do you?
Yes, ma'am, I do.
I mean, I've got everything I need
right here with me.
I got air in my lungs
and a few blank sheets of paper.
I love waking up in the morning
not knowing what's gonna happen ...
or who I'm gonna meet ...
where I'm gonna wind up.
Just the other night I was sleeping
under a bridge, and now ...
here I am on the grandest
ship in the world ...
having champagne with you fine people.
I'll take some more of that.
I figure life is a gift
and I don't intend on wasting it.
You never know what hand
you're gonna get dealt next.
You learn to take life
as it comes at you.
Here you go, Cal.
To make each day count.
- Well said, Jack.
- Hear, hear.
To making it count.
To making it count!
Bravo.
But Mr. Brown had no idea
I'd hidden the money in the stove.
So he comes home drunk as a pig,
celebrating, and he lights a fire.
Bravo.
Next it'll be brandies
in the smoking room.
- Join me in a brandy, gentlemen?
- What a good idea.
Now they retreat into a cloud of smoke
and congratulate each other ...
on being masters of the universe.
Ladies, thank you for the pleasure
of your company.
Rose, may I escort you to the cabin?
No, I'll stay here.
Here you go, Molly.
Joining us, Dawson?
You don't want to stay out here
with the women, do you?
- No, thanks, I've got to be heading back.
- Probably best.
It'll be all business and politics,
that sort of thing.
Wouldn't interest you.
But, Dawson ...
good of you to come.
Jack, must you go?
Time for me to go row
with the other slaves.
Good night, Rose.
So you want to go to a real party?
Is okay if I put my hand here? Okay.
What?
I can't understand you.
I'm going to dance
with her now, all right?
Come on.
- What?
- Come on.
- Come with me.
- Jack! Jack, wait.
I can't do this.
We're gonna have to get
a little bit closer, like this.
You're still my best girl, Cora.
- I don't know the steps.
- Neither do I, just go with it.
Don't think.
Wait, Jack! Stop!
Stop! Wait!
Jack, no.
... beyond the jurisdiction
of the Sherman Act.
So my lawyers will argue.
That's what Rockefeller said, but
the Supreme Court is not swallowing it.
What?
You think a first-class girl
can't drink?
Get out of here.
You all right?
I'm fine.
2 out of 3.
So ...
you think you're big tough men?
Let's see you do this.
Hold this for me, Jack. Hold it up.
Jesus, Mary and Joseph.
- Are you all right?
- I haven't done that in years.
Coffee, sir?
I had hoped you would come to me
last night.
I was tired.
Your exertions below decks were,
no doubt, exhausting.
I see you had that undertaker
of a manservant follow me. How typical.
You will never behave like that again,
Rose, do you understand?
I'm not a foreman in one of
your mills that you can command.
I'm your fiancée.
My fiancée!
Yes, you are, and my wife!
My wife in practice, if not yet
by law. So you will honor me.
You'll honor me the way a wife
is required to honor her husband.
Because I will not be made
out a fool, Rose.
Is this in any way unclear?
No.
Good. Excuse me.
Miss Rose.
- We had a little accident.
- That's all right, Miss Rose.
- Sorry, Trudy.
- It's all right.
Let me help you.
It's all right, miss.
- Tea, Trudy.
- Yes, ma'am.
You are not to see that boy again.
Do you understand me?
Rose, I forbid it.
Stop it, Mother.
You'll give yourself a nosebleed.
This is not a game.
Our situation is precarious.
You know the money's gone.
Of course I know it's gone.
You remind me every day.
Your father left us nothing but a legacy
of bad debts hidden by a good name.
That name is the only card
we have to play.
I don't understand you.
It is a fine match with Hockley.
It will ensure our survival.
How can you put this on my shoulders?
Why are you being so selfish?
I'm being selfish?
Do you want to see me working
as a seamstress?
Is that what you want?
To see our fine things
sold at auction?
Our memories scattered to the winds?
It's so unfair.
Of course it's unfair.
We're women.
Our choices are never easy.
♪ Protect them by Thy guiding hand ♪
♪ From every peril on the land ♪
♪ O spirit whom the Father sent ♪
♪ To spread abroad the firmament ♪
♪ O wind of heaven, by thy might ♪
♪ Save all who dare the eagle's flight ♪
♪ And keep them by Thy watchful ♪
- Hello, Mr. Andrews.
- Hello, Jack.
I just need to talk to somebody
for a second.
- Sir, you're not supposed to be in here.
- I just need to speak to someone.
I was just here last night,
you don't remember me?
No, I'm afraid I don't.
- Now, you're gonna have to turn around.
- He'll tell you.
I just need to talk —
Mr. Hockley and Mrs. Dewitt Bukater ...
continue to be appreciative
of your assistance.
They asked me to give you this
in gratitude.
I don't want your money. Please.
I just —
Also to remind you
that you hold a third-class ticket ...
and that your presence here
is no longer appropriate.
Please, I just wanna speak
to Rose for one second.
Gentlemen, please see Mr. Dawson
gets back to where he belongs ...
and that he stays there.
Yes, sir. Come along, you.
♪ Hear us when we cry to Thee ♪
♪ For those in peril on the sea ♪
And why do you have
2 steering wheels?
- We really only use this near shore.
- Excuse me, sir.
Another ice warning.
This one is from the Noordam.
Thank you, Sparks.
Not to worry.
Quite normal for this time of year.
In fact, we're speeding up.
I've just ordered the last boilers lit.
Okay, son, wind it up tight
like I showed you. That's right.
Okay, now, let it go.
That's excellent.
Mr. Andrews, forgive me ...
I did the sum in my head ...
and with the number of lifeboats
times the capacity you mentioned ...
Forgive me, but it seems that there are
not enough for everyone aboard.
About half, actually.
Rose, you miss nothing, do you?
In fact, I put in
these new-type davits ...
which can take an extra row of boats
inside this one.
But it was thought, by some ...
the deck would look too cluttered.
So, I was overruled.
It's a waste of deck space as it is
in an unsinkable ship.
Sleep soundly, young Rose.
I have built you a good ship,
strong and true.
She's all the lifeboat you need.
Keep heading aft.
The next stop will be the engine room.
Come on.
Jack, this is impossible.
I can't see you.
- I need to talk to you.
- No, Jack. No.
Jack, I'm engaged.
I'm marrying Cal.
I love Cal.
Rose, you're no picnic, all right?
You're a spoiled little brat, even.
But under that,
you're the most amazingly ...
astounding, wonderful girl ...
Woman that I've ever known and —
- Jack, I —
- No, let me try to get this out.
You're making ...
I'm not an idiot.
I know how the world works.
I've got $10 in my pocket.
I have nothing to offer you
and I know that.
I understand.
But I'm too involved now.
You jump, I jump, remember?
I can't turn away without knowing
you'll be all right.
That's all that I want.
Well, I'm fine.
I'll be fine. Really.
Really?
I don't think so.
They have got you trapped, Rose.
And you're gonna die
if you don't break free.
Maybe not right away,
because you're strong ...
but sooner or later, that fire
that I love about you, Rose ...
that fire's going to burn out.
It's not up to you to save me, Jack.
You're right.
Only you can do that.
I'm going back. Leave me alone.
Tell Lucile about the disaster
you had with the stationers.
Of course, the invitations had to be
sent back, twice.
- Oh, my dear.
- And the dreadful bridesmaids' gowns.
Let me tell you,
what an odyssey that has been.
Rose decided she wanted lavender.
She knows I detest the color.
She did it to spite me.
If only you'd come to me sooner.
Ruth saw some of my designs
in La Mode lllustrée ...
they were for the trousseau ...
of the Duchess of Marlborough's youngest
daughter. They were quite charming.
I think you'll agree, my dear,
that together ...
we've created something
of a phoenix from the ashes.
Hello, Jack.
I changed my mind.
They said you might be up here —
Give me your hand.
Now close your eyes.
Go on.
Now step up.
Now hold on to the railing.
Keep your eyes closed.
- Don't peek.
- I'm not.
Step up onto the rail.
Hold on. Hold on.
Keep your eyes closed.
- Do you trust me?
- I trust you.
All right, open your eyes.
I'm flying. Jack.
♪ Come, Josephine,
in my flying machine ♪
♪ Going up she goes, up she goes ♪
That was the last time Titanic
ever saw daylight.
We're up to dusk,
the night of the sinking.
- 6 hours to go.
- Incredible.
There's Smith,
and he's standing there ...
and he's got the iceberg warning
in his fucking hand.
Excuse me, his hand,
and he's ordering more speed.
26 years of experience working
against him.
He figures anything big enough to sink
the ship, they're gonna see in time to turn.
But the ship's too big
with too small a rudder.
Doesn't corner worth a damn.
Everything he knows is wrong.
It's quite proper, I assure you.
This is the sitting room.
- Will this light do?
- What?
Don't artists need good light?
That is true, but I'm not used to working
in such horrible conditions.
Monet!
- You know his work?
- Of course.
Look at his use of color here.
Isn't he great?
I know. It's extraordinary.
Cal insists on carting
this hideous thing everywhere.
Should we be expecting him
anytime soon?
Not as long as the cigars
and brandy hold out.
That's nice. What is it, a sapphire?
A diamond. A very rare diamond.
Jack, I want you to draw me
like one of your French girls.
- Wearing this.
- All right.
Wearing only this.
The last thing I need ...
is another picture of me
looking like a porcelain doll.
As a paying customer ...
I expect to get what I want.
Over on the bed. The couch.
Lie down.
- Tell me when it looks right.
- Put your arm back the way it was.
Put that other arm up,
that hand right by your face there.
Right.
Now, head down.
Eyes to me, keep them on me.
And try to stay still.
So serious.
I believe you are blushing,
Mr. Big Artiste.
I can't imagine
Monsieur Monet blushing.
He does landscapes.
- Just relax your face.
- Sorry.
No laughing.
My heart was pounding the whole time.
It was the most erotic
moment of my life ...
up until then, at least.
So what happened next?
You mean, did we do it?
Sorry to disappoint you, Mr. Bodine.
Jack was very professional.
Thank you.
What are you doing?
Will you put this back
in the safe for me?
- Gentlemen, would you excuse me?
- Sure.
None of the stewards have seen her.
This is absurd. It's a ship.
There's only so many places
she could be.
Lovejoy, find her.
- Clear.
- Yes.
I don't think I've ever seen
such a flat calm.
Like a mill pond.
Not a breath of wind.
It will make
the 'bergs harder to see ...
with no breaking water at the base.
Well, I'm off.
Maintain speed and heading,
Mr. Lightoller.
Yes, sir.
It's getting cold.
- You look nice.
- Miss Rose?
My drawings.
Come on, Jack!
- Wait!
- Go!
- Take us down, quick.
- Quickly! Quickly!
Bye.
Sorry.
- Keep going.
- Thank you, I've got it.
Pretty tough for a valet, this fella.
- Seems more like a cop.
- I think he was.
- Oh, shit.
- Go!
- No, over here!
- Quick!
- Now what?
- What?
More coal for number one, mate.
What are you two doing down here?
You shouldn't be down here.
It could be dangerous!
Carry on. Don't mind us.
You're doing a great job.
Keep up the good work!
Look at what we have here.
Thank you.
Where to, miss?
To the stars.
You nervous?
No.
Put your hands on me, Jack.
It's bloody cold.
You know, I can smell ice, you know.
When it's near.
- Bollocks!
- Well, I can, all right?
Did you ever find those binoculars
for the lookouts?
Haven't seen them since Southampton.
Well, I'll be on my rounds. Cheerio.
You're trembling.
Don't worry, I'll be all right.
- They ran down there.
- All right.
Anything missing?
I've got a better idea.
Gotcha!
Did you see those guys' faces?
Did you see them?
When the ship docks ...
I'm getting off with you.
- This is crazy.
- I know.
It doesn't make any sense.
That's why I trust it.
Here, look at this.
Look at that, would you?
They're a bit warmer than we are.
If that's what it takes for us
to get warm, I'd rather not ...
if it's all the same to you, all right?
Bugger me!
Pick up, you bastards!
- Is anyone there?
- Yes, what do you see?
- Iceberg, right ahead!
- Thank you.
Iceberg, right ahead!
Hard to starboard!
Turn! Smartly!
Full astern!
- Hard over.
- Helm's hard over, sir.
Go, lads, go!
Bring that steam down!
Bring it down!
Shut all the dampers! Shut them!
Hold it.
Now! Engage the reversing engine.
Why ain't they turning?
- Is it hard over?
- It is. Yes, sir, hard over.
Come on. Come on. Turn.
Yes.
It's gonna hit!
Jesus Christ!
Jesus.
- Hard to port!
Get back!
Come on, let's go!
Get out of the door.
They're closing the doors!
Get out!
Get out of the door! Go!
Come on, lads! Go, lads, go!
Out!
Oh, my God.
That was a close shave, wasn't it?
Smell ice, can you? Bleeding Christ!
Note the time and enter it in the log.
What was that, Mr. Murdoch?
An iceberg, sir.
I put her hard to starboard, and ran the
engines full astern, but it was too close.
I tried to port round it, but she hit.
- Close the watertight doors.
- Doors are closed, sir.
- All stop.
- Aye, sir.
Find the carpenter.
Get him to sound the ship.
Yes, sir.
Come on, let's get the hell
out of here.
Come on, hurry up.
Excuse me,
why have the engines stopped?
- I felt a shudder.
- I shouldn't worry, madam.
We've likely thrown a propeller blade.
That's the shudder you felt.
May I bring you anything?
No, thank you.
So, now there's talk of an iceberg.
Did you see anything?
I don't see anything now. Do you?
If this is the direction the rats
are going, that's good enough for me.
Everything's under control.
- You there.
- Sir, there is no emergency.
Yes, there is. I've been robbed.
Get the master-at-arms.
- Now, you moron!
- Yes, sir.
Hey, did I miss the fun?
- Did you see what happened?
- No, I missed it.
Apparently, it hit over there.
Boiler Room 6 is flooded
8 feet above the plate ...
and the mail hold is worse.
She's all buckled in —
- Can you shore up?
- Not unless the pumps get ahead.
Have you seen the damage
in the mail hold?
No, she's already underwater.
This is bad.
We should tell Mother and Cal.
I think they're very good, sir.
Don't touch anything.
I want the entire room photographed.
We've been looking for you, miss.
Here we go.
Something serious has happened.
Yes, it has.
Indeed.
Two things dear to me
have disappeared this evening.
Now that one is back, I have a pretty
good idea where to find the other.
Search him.
- Take your coat off, son.
- Now what?
Come on, now.
Cal, what are you doing?
We're in the middle of an emergency.
What's going on?
- Is this it?
- That's it.
This is horseshit!
Don't you believe it, Rose. Don't.
- He couldn't have.
- Of course he could.
It's easy enough for a professional.
But I was with him the whole time.
This is absurd.
Perhaps he did it while you were putting
your clothes back on, dear.
Real slick, Cal.
Rose, they put it in my pocket.
- Shut up.
- It isn't even your pocket. Is it, son?
"Property of A.L. Ryerson."
That was reported stolen today.
I just borrowed it.
I was gonna return it.
An honest thief.
We have an honest thief here, do we?
You know I didn't do this, Rose.
You know it.
Don't believe them, Rose. You know it.
- You know I didn't do it.
- Come on, son. Let's go.
- Rose!
- Come on, there's a good lad.
Come on.
You know I didn't do it. You know me!
This is most unfortunate, Captain.
Water 14 feet above the keel
in 10 minutes ...
in the forepeak, in all 3 holds,
and in Boiler Room 6.
- That's right, sir.
- When can we get underway, damn it?
That's 5 compartments.
She can stay afloat with the
first 4 compartments breached ...
but not 5.
Not 5.
As she goes down by the head ...
the water will spill over the tops
of the bulkheads at "E" deck ...
from one to the next, back and back.
There's no stopping it.
The pumps. We open the pumps ...
The pumps buy you time,
but minutes only.
From this moment,
no matter what we do ...
Titanic will founder.
But this ship can't sink.
She's made of iron, sir.
I assure you, she can. And she will.
It is a mathematical certainty.
How much time?
An hour. Two, at most.
And how many aboard, Mr. Murdoch?
2,200 souls on board, sir.
Well, I believe you may
get your headlines, Mr. Ismay.
Oh, it is a little slut, isn't it?
You look at me
when I'm talking to you!
- Mr. Hockley?
- Not now. We're busy.
Sir, I've been told to ask you
to put on your lifebelts ...
and come up to the boat deck.
- I said, not now.
I'm sorry to inconvenience you,
Mr. Hockley, but it's Captain's orders.
Now please, dress warmly.
It's quite cold out tonight.
Now, may I suggest topcoats and hats?
This is ridiculous.
Not to worry, miss.
I'm sure it's just a precaution.
Everybody up. Lifebelts on.
What's he on about?
- Everybody up. Put your lifebelts on.
- What's the ruckus?
Just put your lifebelts on.
CQD?
Sir?
That's right, CQD, the distress call.
That's our position.
Tell whoever responds that we're
going down by the head ...
and need immediate assistance.
Blimey.
Keep lowering!
Steady! Make it taut! And winch out!
Uncover this boat!
Uncover all the boats aft!
Release those ties!
Roll back that cover! Smartly now!
Mr. Wilde, where are the passengers?
They've all gone back inside.
Too damn cold and noisy for them.
You there!
Get down here
and help with these lines!
Care for a drink, sir?
Please put your lifebelts on.
Sonny, what's doing?
You got us all trussed up here
and now we're cooling our heels.
Sorry, ma'am. Let me go find out.
I don't think anybody knows
what the hell's going on around here.
It's just the goddamned English,
doing everything by the book.
There's no need
for language, Mr. Hockley.
Go back and turn the heaters on
in our rooms.
I'd like a cup of tea when I return.
- Yes, ma'am.
Mr. Andrews ...
I saw the iceberg.
And I see it in your eyes.
Please tell me the truth.
The ship will sink.
- You're certain?
- Yes.
In an hour or so ...
all this will be
at the bottom of the Atlantic.
What?
Please, tell only who you must.
I don't want to be
responsible for a panic.
And get to a boat.
Quickly. Don't wait.
You remember
what I told you about the boats?
Yes.
I understand.
Yes, madam,
please put it on immediately.
Over here, son.
Sir, they need you up
at the second-class purser's office.
- There's a big mob up there.
- Go on. I'll keep an eye on him.
Aye. Right.
Sir!
Carpathia says they're making 17 knots.
Full steam for them, sir.
She's the only one who's responding?
The only one close, sir.
Says they can be here in 4 hours.
4 hours!
Thank you, Bride.
My God.
We are swung out and ready, sir.
Hadn't we better get the women
and children into the boats, sir?
Yes.
Sir?
Women and children first, yes.
Yes, sir.
Ladies and gentlemen,
your attention, please!
Step this way, please. That's right.
Come towards me. Thank you.
Good.
For the time being, I shall
require only women and children.
- Gentlemen, please.
- Right here.
All right, boys. Like the Captain said,
nice and cheery, so there's no panic.
Wedding Dance.
Lifebelts on. Put your lifebelts on.
Here, put your lifebelt on.
Yeah, come on. Put your lifebelt on.
Turn that around.
Please.
It isn't time to go up to the boats yet!
Please stay calm.
Make sure, everybody,
you've got your lifebelts on.
And, gentlemen, allow the women
and children through to the front.
- What are we doing, Mommy?
- We're just waiting, dear.
When they finish putting
first-class people in the boats ...
they will be starting with us
and we'll want to be all ready, won't we?
Everybody, not just right yet.
Don't push on the gates.
You won't get out any faster.
- Someone help.
- Go and get some help.
Lower it away, left and right together!
Both sides together! Steady!
Steady!
Stop!
Hold the left side!
Right side only!
Right side only. Hold the left side!
Lower away together!
Steady, lads!
You know,
I do believe this ship may sink.
I've been asked to give you
this small token of our appreciation.
Compliments of Mr. Caledon Hockley.
Come on, sister. You heard the man.
Into the boat.
Any room for a gentleman, gentlemen?
Only women at this time, sir.
Will the lifeboats be seated
according to class?
I hope they're not too crowded.
Oh, Mother, shut up!
Don't you understand?
The water is freezing
and there aren't enough boats.
Not enough by half.
Half the people on this ship
are going to die.
Not the better half.
Come on, Ruth, get in the boat.
First-class seats are right up here.
You know, it's a pity
I didn't keep that drawing.
It'll be worth a lot more by morning.
Women and children
towards the front, please.
You unimaginable bastard.
Come on, Rose, darling.
There's plenty of room for you.
Right this way, miss.
Come on, Rose.
You're next, darling.
Come into the boat, Rose.
Come.
Rose?
Get into the boat.
Goodbye, Mother.
Rose?
- Rose, come back here.
- Where are you going?
To him?
What, to be a whore to a gutter rat?
No, wait.
I'd rather be his whore
than your wife.
No!
I said, no!
Rose, please stop!
- Lower away!
- No, stop!
- All together.
- No, wait!
Lower away!
Rose!
Help!
Can anybody hear me?
Hello! Help me!
Mr. Andrews!
- Steward, check the starboard corridor.
- Yes, Mr. Andrews.
Madam, please, put on a lifebelt.
Get to the boat deck immediately.
Lucy, for God's sake, put on
a lifebelt and set a good example.
Yes, sir.
- Anyone in here?
- Mr. Andrews?
Thank God.
Where would the master-at-arms
take someone under arrest?
- You have to get to a boat right away.
- No!
I'm doing this with or
without your help, sir.
But without will take longer.
Take the elevator to the very bottom.
Go to the left.
Down the crewmen's passage, then
go right and left again at the stairs.
You'll come to a long corridor.
This could be bad.
Oh, shit!
Excuse me. Thank you.
- I do not care what you think, sir.
- Lifts are closed.
I'm sorry, miss,
but the lifts are closed.
I'm through being polite,
God damn it! Now, take me down!
"E" deck.
Come on.
- I'm going back up.
- No.
Come back! I'm going back up!
Crew passage.
Jack!
Rose!
Rose, I'm in here!
Jack!
- Jack!
- Rose!
Jack! Jack, I'm sorry.
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
- That guy, Lovejoy, put it in my pocket.
- I know. I know.
Listen, Rose ...
you're gonna have to find
a spare key, all right?
Look in that cabinet right there.
It's a little silver one, Rose.
Silver.
These are all brass ones!
Check right here, Rose.
Rose ...
how'd you find out I didn't do it?
I didn't.
I just realized I already knew.
Keep looking.
No key. There's no key!
All right, Rose, listen.
You're gonna have to go
find some help.
It'll be all right.
I'll be right back.
I'll just wait here!
Hello? Is there anyone here?
Hello?
Is there anybody down here?
We need help! Hello?
Damn it.
Can anybody hear me, please? Hello?
Oh, thank God.
Wait, I need your help.
There's a man back here.
Wait!
Hello?
Miss, you shouldn't be here now.
- I need your help.
- We'll get you topside. This way, quickly.
There's a man down here. He's trapped.
- This way. There is no need to panic.
- Please!
No, I'm not panicking!
You're going the wrong way!
Let go of me! Listen!
The hell with you.
Oh, my God.
Jack!
Rose!
Will this work?
I guess we'll find out. Come on.
Wait.
Try a couple
of practice swings over there.
Good. Now try to hit the same
mark again, Rose. You can do it.
Okay. That's enough practice.
Come on, Rose. You can do it.
Listen, just hit it really hard
and really fast.
Come on. Wait.
Open your hands up a little more.
- Good.
- Like that?
Right.
Listen, Rose, I trust you.
Go.
You did it!
Come on, let's go.
Oh, shit, this is cold!
This is the way out.
We have to find another way.
Come on.
Now there's something
you don't see every day.
What's this luggage doing here?
Get rid of it. We need the room.
Get rid of that! Out!
Come. Time for her to go, sir.
Step back.
- Keep calm. Sit down.
- No.
- No!
- Make more room.
That's right. Look sharp.
Lovejoy.
She's not on the starboard side, either.
We're running out of time.
This strutting martinet
isn't letting any men on at all.
There's one on the other side
letting men on.
Then that's our play.
We'll need some insurance first.
Come on.
Come on, this way, please.
All the way down there.
Here!
What do you think you're doing?
You'll have to pay for that, you know.
- That's White Star Line property.
- Shut up!
Will you hold the boat a moment?
I just have to run back to my room ...
- Sit down.
- She's the last.
Mr. Lightoller, why are the boats
being launched half-full?
- Not now, Mr. Andrews.
- There, look.
20 or so in a boat built for 65?
And I saw one boat with only 12. 12!
We weren't sure of the weight,
Mr. Andrews.
- These boats may buckle.
- Rubbish!
They were tested in Belfast
with the weight of 70 men.
Now fill these boats, Mr. Lightoller.
For God's sake, man!
Please, I need more
women and children!
Get back in there!
This is not an exit.
Get back in there.
You can't keep us locked in here
like animals. The ship's bloody sinking.
Bring forward the women.
Unlock the gates.
Women only!
Lock the gates!
For God's sake, man, there are
women and children down here!
Let us up, so we can have a chance!
Get back!
- Jack.
- Tommy.
- Can we get out?
- It's hopeless that way.
Whatever we do,
we've got to do it fast.
Jack!
Fabrizio.
The boats are all gone.
This whole place is flooding.
We've got to get out.
- There is niente this way.
- All right.
Let's go this way,
all right? Come on.
- I make my own luck.
- So do I.
Come on!
No, come on, let's go this way.
This way.
Just go back to the main stairwell
and everything will be sorted out there.
The hell it will.
It will all get sorted out back there.
Go back to the main stairwell.
- Open the gate.
- Go back down the main stairwell.
Open the gate right now.
Go back down the main stairwell
like I told you!
God damn it! Son of a bitch!
Stop that!
Open the damn gate!
Fabri, Tommy, give me hand here.
- Move aside. Move aside!
- Pull!
Pull!
- Move aside.
- Put that down!
- Move aside!
- One! Two!
- Stop that!
Three!
Again!
Let's go!
Let's go, Rose.
You can't go up there!
You can't do this!
Keep order here!
Get back. Get back!
Hold on to her!
Pull her in.
Get back, I say ...
or I'll shoot you all like dogs!
Keep order here!
Keep order, I say.
Mr. Lowe, man this boat.
Right.
Is everybody all right? Nobody panic.
Stay back!
We're too late.
There are more boats down the front.
Stay with this one. Murdoch.
He seems to be quite practical.
Stop lowering!
Cut the falls!
Sit down!
Stay back, you lot! Just stay back!
Stay back, the lot of you!
Just stay back!
It's starting to fall apart.
We don't have much time.
Mr. Murdoch?
Mr. Hockley. You two, with me, now!
I'm a businessman, as you know,
I have a business proposition for you.
Come on, Rose.
The boats are gone!
Colonel, are there any boats
on that side?
No, miss, but there are a couple
of boats all the way forward.
This way, I'll lead you.
What's the use?
Nobody's listening to us anyway.
They don't listen to us at dinner, either.
Come on, let's play. Keep us warm.
Orpheus.
Music to drown by.
Now I know I'm in first class.
- Where is everyone?
- They're all still aft, sir.
Come on, madam, don't cry.
We have an understanding,
then, Mr. Murdoch.
Will the men please hold back?
Hold back, I say!
Women and children only! Get back!
I said, step back, sir.
Come through, madam.
This way. Step back, sir!
Let the women —
You better check the other side. Go!
I found her, on the other side.
Waiting for a boat ...
with him.
- Any more women and children?
- They're all aboard, Mr. Murdoch.
Anyone else then?
- Hop on, sir.
- Anyone else?
Do hurry. Hurry along.
Stand by the falls.
God damn it all to hell.
Shit.
Fire!
Sir, you can't go through here.
Sir, you can't go through.
That's it. Splendid. Right.
Prepare to lower!
Ready on the left!
Take them down.
Keep it steady.
Both sides together.
Steady. Keep it steady.
- Give her to me.
- Daddy.
- It'll be fine, darling. Don't you worry.
- Take her.
Daddy, get in the boat.
It's goodbye for a little while.
Only for a little while.
There'll be another
boat for the daddies ...
this boat's for the mommies
and the children.
You hold Mommy's hand
and be a good little girl.
I'm not going without you.
- No. You have to go, now.
- No, Jack.
Get in the boat, Rose.
No, Jack.
Yes. Get on the boat.
Yes, get on the boat, Rose.
My God. Look at you.
You look a fright.
Here.
Put this on. Come on.
Go on. I'll get the next one.
No, not without you.
I'll be all right.
Listen, I'll be fine.
I'm a survivor, all right?
Don't worry about me.
Now, go on. Get on.
I have an arrangement with an officer
on the other side of the ship.
Jack and I can get off safely.
Both of us.
See? I got my own boat to catch.
- Go.
- Come on, hurry. They're almost full.
Step aboard, miss.
- Go.
- Come on, hurry.
- Step aboard, please.
- You're Daddy's good girl.
- Step lively!
- Keep back.
Keep back, I say.
Clear the rail, please.
Lower away!
Steady.
And lower away evenly, lads.
Easy.
Lower away.
You're a good liar.
Almost as good as you.
Easy, now. And lower away.
There's no ...
There's no arrangement, is there?
No, there is.
Not that you'll benefit much from it.
And even away.
I always win, Jack.
And lower away evenly, lads.
One way or another.
Watch that trim. Trim that boat.
Easy.
Even, lads.
Keep going!
Rose!
- Stop her!
- Rose!
- What are you doing?
- Stop her!
No!
Rose!
You're so stupid!
Why did you do that?
You're so stupid, Rose.
Why did you do that? Why?
You jump, I jump, right?
Right.
Oh, God.
I couldn't go. I couldn't go, Jack.
It's all right.
We'll think of something.
At least I'm with you.
Come on! Move!
Come on!
Move!
Come on, come on, Rose!
Rose, come on!
Move, Rose!
Go!
I hope you enjoy your time together!
What could possibly be funny?
I put the diamond in the coat.
And I put the coat on her!
Come on.
Dada!
We can't leave him.
All right, come on!
Dada!
Go back!
That's the wrong way! Come back!
Go!
Run, Rose!
Jack!
- Jack!
- Rose!
This way!
Come on!
Give me your hand!
Oh, God!
Help!
Wait, sir! Sir,
open the gate, please!
- Please!
- Please, help us!
Bloody hell!
Hurry.
- Come on, come on!
- Come on!
Go, go!
Jesus.
- Please!
- Come on!
Hurry!
Come on!
I'm sorry, I dropped the keys.
- Wait, please!
- Wait!
Don't leave! Please, send for help!
I got it! Which one is it, Rose?
The short one. Try the short one.
Hurry, Jack.
Oh, no! No, it won't go in.
It's stuck! It's stuck!
- Come on!
- Hurry, Jack!
Hurry, Jack!
I got it! Go, Rose!
Go!
Jack!
Come on!
Move, move.
- Get those oars in place.
- Get an oar under it.
Women and children only, damn you!
Hold it!
Get these davits cranked in!
Let's get the falls hooked up!
Stay back!
Mommy!
Stay back, sir!
Stay back, I say.
Keep going up!
Stop pushing!
Stay back!
Will you give us a chance to live,
you limey bastard?
I'll shoot any man who tries
to get past me! Get back!
Bastard!
Get back!
We had a deal, damn it!
Your money can't save you anymore
than it can save me. Get back!
Women and children only!
Stop pushing!
No, Tommy!
No! No, Tommy!
Bastardo!
No, Will!
Now stand back, damn you!
Gently, hold it.
I have a child!
Clear a path!
Please, I have a child.
Please, I'm all she has in the world.
Go on.
Step back!
Please!
Here. Give her to me.
There, there.
Wait! Mr. Andrews.
Oh, Rose.
Won't you even make a try for it?
I'm sorry that I didn't build you
a stronger ship, young Rose.
It's going fast. We have to move.
Wait.
Good luck to you, Rose.
And to you.
Mr. Guggenheim? These are for you.
No, thank you.
We are dressed in our best ...
and are prepared to go down
as gentlemen.
But we would like a brandy.
Get the falls over here now!
Make them taut. Then we'll right it!
Capitain, Capitain,
where should I go? Please.
Captain. Sir.
Right. That's it, then.
Goodbye, Wally, good luck.
- Goodbye, Wallace.
- So long, old chap.
And so they lived happily
together for 300 years ...
in the land of "Tir na nÓg" ...
land of eternal youth and beauty.
There's no time! Cut the falls!
Cut them if you have to!
I need a knife!
Cut the falls now! Cut them loose!
Cut those bloody falls!
Gentlemen, it has been a privilege
playing with you tonight.
We have to stay on the ship
as long as possible.
Come on.
This way. Hold the rail.
Come on, Rose. Jump.
Come on.
I got you. Jump!
I've got you, miss.
- Jack!
- What?
Back!
No, you'll swamp us!
Nobody panic.
Yea, though I walk through the
valley of the shadow of death —
You want to walk a little faster
through that valley, there?
Holy Mary, Mother of God,
pray for us, sinners ...
now and at the hour
of our death. Amen.
Hail Mary, full of grace ...
This way.
Come on!
And I saw a new heaven
and a new Earth.
For the first heaven and the
first Earth had passed away ...
and there was no more sea.
It'll be over soon.
It'll all be over soon.
And he shall dwell with them ...
and they shall be his people ...
and God himself shall be with them
and be their God.
Jack ...
this is where we first met.
And God shall wipe away
all the tears from their eyes ...
and there shall be no more death ...
neither shall there
be sorrow or crying ...
be any more pain ...
for the former world has passed away.
Bloody pull faster! And pull!
Hang on, Miss Trudy!
Hold on real tight.
God almighty!
Keep those breakers in! Keep them in!
We have to move!
Give me your hand, I'll pull you over.
Come on, give me your hand.
I've got you. I won't let go.
Come on, I've got you.
- What's happening, Jack?
- I don't know.
- Hold on!
- Jack!
Somebody help me, please!
This is it!
Oh, my God, Jack!
Hold on!
The ship is gonna suck us down.
Take a deep breath when I say.
Kick for the surface and keep kicking.
Do not let go of my hand.
We're going to make it, Rose. Trust me.
I trust you.
Ready? Now!
Jack!
- Rose!
- Jack!
Jack!
Get off her!
- Rose!
- Jack!
Swim, Rose! I need you to swim!
Keep swimming.
- It's so cold.
- Swim, Rose!
Come on. Here.
Keep swimming. Come on.
Here, get on it.
Get on top.
Come on, Rose.
Stay on it. Stay on, Rose.
It'll be all right now.
You'll be all right now.
Return the boats!
The boats are coming
back for us, Rose.
Hold on just a little bit longer.
They had to row away
for the suction ...
but now they'll be coming back.
For God's sake!
Please help us!
You don't understand.
If we go back, they'll swamp the boat.
They'll pull us right down, I'm telling you.
Knock it off. You're scaring me.
Come on, girls, grab an oar. Let's go.
Are you out of your mind? We're in
the middle of the North Atlantic.
Now, do you people want to live
or do you want to die?
I don't understand a one of you.
What's the matter with you?
It's your men out there!
There's plenty of room for more.
And there'll be one less on this boat.
If you don't shut
that hole in your face!
Bring in your oars over there.
Tie these two boats together as well.
Now, make sure that's tied up
nice and tight.
Right, listen to me, men.
We have to go back.
I want to transfer all the women
from this boat into that boat right now.
As quick as you can, please.
Let's create some space over there.
Move forward and out.
It's getting quiet.
It's just going to take a couple of
minutes to get the boats organized.
I don't know about you ...
but I intend to write
a strongly-worded letter ...
to the White Star Line about all this.
I love you, Jack.
Don't you do that.
Don't you say your goodbyes.
Not yet. Do you understand me?
I'm so cold.
Listen, Rose ...
you're gonna get out of here.
You're gonna go on ...
and you're gonna make lots of babies.
And you're gonna watch them grow.
You're gonna die an old lady,
warm in her bed.
Not here.
Not this night.
Not like this.
Do you understand me?
I can't feel my body.
Winning that ticket was the best thing
that ever happened to me.
It brought me to you.
And I'm thankful for that, Rose.
I'm thankful.
You must ...
do me this honor.
You must promise me that you'll survive.
That you won't give up ...
no matter what happens.
No matter how hopeless.
Promise me now, Rose.
And never let go of that promise.
I promise.
Never let go.
I'll never let go, Jack.
I'll never let go.
Right ahead, sir.
Oars!
Do you see any moving?
No, sir. None moving, sir.
Check them.
Bring that oar up here.
Check them. Make sure.
These are dead, sir.
Now give way. Ahead easy.
Careful with your oars.
Don't hit them.
Is there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
We waited too long.
Keep checking them! Keep looking!
Is there anyone alive out there?
Can anyone hear me?
♪ In my flying machine ♪
♪ And up she goes ♪
♪ Up she goes ♪
♪ Come, Josephine ♪
♪ In my flying machine ♪
Jack?
There's a boat.
There's a boat, Jack.
Come back.
Come back!
Hello!
Can anyone hear me?
There's nothing here, sir.
Come back.
I'll never let go. I promise.
Come about!
1,500 people went into the sea ...
when Titanic sank from under us.
There were 20 boats floating nearby ...
and only one came back.
One.
6 were saved from the water ...
myself included.
6 out of 1,500.
Afterward,
the 700 people in the boats ...
had nothing to do but wait.
Wait to die, wait to live.
Wait for an absolution ...
that would never come.
Sir, I don't think you'll find
any of your people down here.
It's all steerage.
His hair is reddish brown,
and a white beard.
- Isn't there another passenger list?
- There's no other list.
- Perhaps he's on another ship.
- We're doing all we can.
That's the last time I ever saw him.
He married, of course,
and inherited his millions.
But the crash of '29
hit his interests hard.
And he put a pistol
in his mouth that year.
Or so I read.
Can I take your name, please, love?
Dawson.
Rose Dawson.
Thank you.
We never found anything on Jack.
There's no record of him at all.
No, there wouldn't be, would there?
And I've never spoken of him
until now. Not to anyone.
Not even your grandfather.
A woman's heart
is a deep ocean of secrets.
But now you know there was a
man named Jack Dawson ...
and that he saved me ...
in every way
that a person can be saved.
I don't even have a picture of him.
He exists now only in my memory.
Keldysh, Mir-2 on our way
to the surface.
I was saving this
for when I found the diamond.
I'm sorry.
3 years.
I've thought of nothing
except Titanic.
But I never got it.
I never let it in.
♪ Every night in my dreams ♪
♪ I see you ♪
♪ I feel you ♪
♪ That is how I know you go on. ♪
♪ Far across the distance ♪
♪ And spaces between us ♪
♪ You have come to show you go on. ♪
♪ Near ♪
♪ Far ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
♪ I believe that the heart does go on. ♪
♪ Once more ♪
♪ you open the door ♪
♪ and you're here in my heart ♪
♪ and my heart will go on and on. ♪
♪ Love can touch just one time ♪
♪ and last for a lifetime ♪
♪ and never let go till we're gone. ♪
♪ Love was when I loved you ♪
♪ One true time I hold to ♪
♪ In my life we'll always go on. ♪
♪ Near ♪
♪ Far ♪
♪ Wherever you are ♪
♪ I believe that the heart does go on. ♪
♪ Once more ♪
♪ you open the door ♪
♪ and you're here in my heart ♪
♪ and my heart will go on and on. ♪
♪ You're here ♪
♪ There's nothing I fear ♪
♪ And I know that my heart will go on. ♪
♪ We'll stay ♪
♪ forever this way ♪
♪ You are safe in my heart ♪
♪ and my heart will go on and on ♪
♪ and love ...